

TRISHA KAYE P. MASBATE, RMT, MLS(ASCPi)

540 E 500 S, Apartment 215, Salt Lake City, Utah 84102

Email: trisha.masbate@gmail.com

Mobile No.: +13858318934

Provides services of both a technical and non-technical nature in the laboratory service areas. Performs routine and complex laboratory tests in an assigned department of the clinical laboratory to provide physicians with rapid and accurate laboratory test results. Works

independently and in a team environment to demonstrate enhanced knowledge, technical skills, problem solving, leadership, education, and administrative abilities. Works under the direction of specialist, lead and/or supervisor.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Born on March 17, 1996 in Davao City.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

BACHELOR IN MEDICAL LABORATORY SCIENCE, graduated as Magna Cum Laude and Valedictorian in March 2016 at San Pedro College. Academic Scholarship and Davao EBSU-STEP Scholarship grantee. Consistent Dean's Lister.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

As a Medical Laboratory Scientist

Currently a Medical Laboratory Scientist II NYQ at Associated Regional and University Pathologists (ARUP) Laboratories in Department 897 – Clinical Toxicology 3 on the determination of the exposure of newborns to drugs in utero and the presence of explicit drug abuse. Also adept on the services offered by Department 811 – Hemostasis/Thrombosis on specialized testing to aid in the diagnosis of multiple and complex coagulopathies.

A Senior Medical Laboratory Scientist, a proficient Water Microbiologist, an awarded Star Employee, and a Laboratory Ambassadress at Davao Doctors Hospital - a privately-owned, tertiary-level institution with a 250-bed capacity and a Gold Accreditation from Accreditation Canada International (ACI).

A Senior Lab Staff who performed diagnostic laboratory procedures, both manual and automated, in Clinical Microscopy, Hematology, Clinical Chemistry, Immunology, Serology, Microbiology, Blood Bank and Histopathology; complied with the Daily Maintenance and Quality Control and Assurance in all analyzers; instructed MLS interns during internship; and, trained to give the unparalleled standard of patient care possible.

As a Clinical Instructor/Professor

A full-time Clinical Instructor conducting Continuing Education Program (CEP) and Skills Laboratory on Immunology, Serology and Blood Banking (ISBB) for the Fourth Year Medical Laboratory Science interns at San Pedro College.

A full-time Professor of the Medical Laboratory Science Department of San Pedro College handling Blood Banking, Bacteriology, Immunology and Serology, Histopathologic Techniques, and Principles in Medical Laboratory Science.

For SY 2017-2018 and SY 2018-2019, a part-time Clinical Instructor for ISBB CEP and Skills Laboratory. For SY 2016-2017, a part-time Clinical Instructor for Microbiology CEP and Skills Laboratory.

AFFILIATIONS

ARUP Laboratories

- -Medical Laboratory Scientist II NYQ, Clinical Toxicology 3 (June 2022 Present)
- -Medical Laboratory Scientist II, Hemostasis/Thrombosis (May 2021 June 2022)

Davao Doctors Hospital

-Medical Laboratory Scientist (Training: September 2016) (October 2016-November 2019)

San Pedro College

- -Part-time Clinical Instructor and CEP/Skills Laboratory Instructor (November 2016-August 2019)
- -Full-time Clinical Instructor and CEP/Skills Laboratory Instructor/Professor (November 2019-March 2021)

PROFESSIONAL DUTIES

- 1. Receives request and explains to patient the nature of the procedures to be done and releasing schedules
- 2. Receives, collects and labels specimen from patient
- 3. Analyzes and interprets lab reports with highest level of accuracy
- 4. Operates and calibrates laboratory equipment; maintains cleanliness of each laboratory area
- 5. Ensures maintenance and safe, orderly and efficient control of equipment and supplies in the laboratory
- 6. Collaborates seamlessly with clinicians regarding unclear requests, critical results and patient's possible diagnosis
- 7. Coordinates with all hospital sections as required by day-to-day operations, in the process complying with hospital policies, rules and

- regulations and the standards for the faithful delivery of service to patients
- 8. Consistently implements the quality objectives and procedures
- 9. Undertakes action to correct non-conformity that might be observed or found over the work area
- 10. Performs new work as may be assigned by the Laboratory Head/Chief Medical Technologist.

CERTIFICATES OF TRAININGS AND SEMINARS

3rd Madayaw International Multidisciplinary Research Conference 2020 "Shaping the Future of Research Emerging from the COVID-19 Pandemic" San Pedro College Davao City

Crime Scene Biosafety: Law Enforcement and First Responders during COVID-19
Philippine Association of Medical Technologists, Inc.
BioRisk Association of the Philippines
Davao City

COVID-19 and ONE Health: Focus on Animal Safety Philippine Association of Medical Technologists, Inc. BioRisk Association of the Philippines Davao City

Basic Life Support Training for Healthcare Professionals
Davao Doctors Hospital Learning and Developlment Department
Oncology Building, Davao Doctors Hospital, Davao City

Managing Stress for Health and Wellness

Philippine Association of Medical Technologists – Davao Chapter Medical Arts Building, San Pedro Hospital, Davao City

CODE BLUE | Enemies Of The Heart

Davao Doctors Hospital Learning and Development Office Oncology Building, Davao Doctors Hospital, Davao City

Proficiency Training Course on Water Microbiological Analysis

National Reference Laboratory - East Avenue Medical Center Audio Visual Room, Pauline Guilmette Building, San Pedro College, Davao City

Show Me The Value: Financial Nuts And Bolts For Clinical Laboratory

Department of Medical Laboratory Science Philomene Labrecque Hall, San Pedro College, Davao City

Diagnostic Parasitology Seminar

Department of Medical Laboratory Science Philomene Labrecque Hall, San Pedro College, Davao City

Pancreatic Cancer Seminar

Department of Medical Laboratory Science Philomene Labrecque Hall, San Pedro College, Davao City

Work Ethics Seminar

Department of Medical Laboratory Science Philomene Labrecque Hall, San Pedro College, Davao City

Anti-Bullying Campaign | STOP (Self Transformation Of People): Ending the Clutches of Long Habits and Practice Through Awareness

SALIGAN Supreme Student Council Philomene Labrecque Hall, San Pedro College, Davao City

Awareness Campaign on Mental Health with Topics on Depression, Suicide and Rights of Mentally Ill Patients

San Pedro College, Davao City

HIV/AIDS Awareness Campaign Symposium

SALIGAN Supreme Student Council San Pedro College, Davao City

EQUIPMENT HANDLED

Stago Machineries, ORTHO VISION Analyzer for Blood Bank, Sysmex XN-1000, Sysmex CA-600 Series, Beckman Coulter UniCel DxH 800, Tulip ErySed, Sysmex UF-1000i, Arkray Aution Hybrid, Sysmex UF-5000, Abbott ARCHITECT i1000SR, Abbott ARCHITECT c4000, Abbott ARCHITECT ci4100, HBV DNA PCR, Christie VeinViewer 2.0 – Vision, Roche Elecsys 2010, Roche Cobas e 411, Beckman-Coulter Access 2, Beckman Coulter DxC 800, Beckman ACL Elite Pro, BioMérieux BacT/ALERT 3D, BioMérieux VITEK 2, ESCO Class II Biological Safety Cabinet, Getein Biotechnology FIA8000, Roche Cobas h 232, BD BACTEC FX40, Biorad D-10

HONORS AND AWARDS RECEIVED

Valedictorian

Magna Cum Laude

PASMETH Gold Medal Award for Academic Excellence

Outstanding Involvement in Extra and Co-curricular Activities Most Outstanding Ambassador for the Ancillary Department Certified International Medical Laboratory Scientist (ASCPi) Certificate No. 6864

REFERENCE PERSONS

ASHLEY SUMSION

Supervisor
Department of Clinical Toxicology 3
ARUP Laboratories
ashley.sumsion@aruplab.com
801-388-1916

STEPHANIE NOURSE

Lead
Department of Clinical Toxicology 3
ARUP Laboratories
stephanie.nourse@aruplab.com
801-603-3025

DR. AILEEN GRACE L. ANG, RMT, MSMT, MSBio, PhD

Assistant Dean
Department of Medical Laboratory Science
San Pedro College
<u>aileengrace_ang@spcdavao.edu.ph</u>
+639171648868

JHASPER E. ARREOLA, RMT

Blood Bank/Immunohematology Section Head Department of Laboratory and Pathology Davao Doctors Hospital jearreola@ddh.com.ph jhasperestrella@yahoo.com +639171499306